<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Co-create Change</title><atom:link href="https://cocreatechange.in/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><link>https://cocreatechange.in</link><description>Changing the way we change</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate><generator>Wintersmith - https://github.com/jnordberg/wintersmith</generator><language>en</language><item><title>Workplace Mental Health</title><link>https://cocreatechange.in/articles/workplace/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://cocreatechange.in/articles/workplace/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;A shout out to heads of organizations talking of addressing workplace stress. While one needs to applaud the initiative, please don’t airdrop ‘experts’ who are not trained in the facilitative dimensions of Mental Health to address your employee’s wellbeing.
My office is increasingly getting inundated by individuals who emerge more stressed than relieved from such workplace benevolence. Please trash the “very insightful” feedback your stress busting initiatives may have elicited. Employees, even millennials are sometimes too vulnerable to be genuine. There’s plenty at stake. You as their bosses don’t get to know how your well-meaning efforts carry the potential to screw people up further. That’s a narrative that unravels in our offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A therapist’s repertoire of life enhancing skills are not acquired through watching YouTube videos, listening to podcasts, to celebrities and media personnel and various ‘other domain experts’ spewing wisdom. Nor is it acquired through Optimize, Audible and Blinkist. Our training puts us through a rigorous bootcamp of experiencing what it feels like to hit a dead - end, of going through the discomfort of drowning, of not being rescued while we “gulp in” water, of dealing with the undertow even when swimming with the tide… and all this through sharing our real life problems. Over and above this we learn and practice more than a hundred different interventions for problem management and opportunity development.
Till you have walked in those shoes, till you have experienced the vulnerability of sharing, of disclosures, of raw emotional pain, of fumbling your way towards a solution; anything you trot out because you’re well intentioned is most likely damaging if not cute. If you haven’t been there and done that … Don’t try it on others! As experts we are tired of doing damage control, or worse still, have people lose faith in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description></item><item><title>My Stanford Diary</title><link>https://cocreatechange.in/articles/Stanford/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 05:30:00 +0630</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://cocreatechange.in/articles/Stanford/</guid><author></author><description>&lt;p&gt;My #StanfordDiary
Feeling elated to be spearheading the new TEAM-CBT techniques in India &amp;amp; Asia. 
This is literally #CBT on steroids ….!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A journey that started a year back culminated with the fall semester (2019) at #StanfordUniversity. It was a mind blowing experience to undergo intensive classroom &amp;amp; personal training under coach &amp;amp; mentor Dr. David Burns, a pioneer in the development of cognitive therapy &amp;amp; creator of the new TEAM therapy. Dr Burns is a clinical adjunct emeritus Professor of psychiatry at the Stanford Medical School. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were times when the mountain trail was our practice track &amp;amp; nature our co-therapist! Where learning was coupled with love, warmth, laughter &amp;amp; indulgence! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt surreal as one made a place for ones self at the high table. Where discussions centred around  testing, the 5 secrets of effective  communication, melting away resistance, the role of paradoxical agenda setting, the magic dial, externalisation of voices, individual &amp;amp; interpersonal downward arrow &amp;amp; a 150 other brilliant  methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capturing the best moments of life … while FEELING GOOD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;90%&quot; height=&quot;538&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TtIwfsSi-ac&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;



</description></item></channel></rss>